<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RCE - Releases</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/feeds/releases.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rcenvironment.de/</id><updated>2019-03-13T14:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>RCE 9.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/rce-90.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-13T14:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-13T14:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2019-03-13:/rce-90.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We recently released RCE 9.0, which includes new features as well as improvements to existing ones.
In the following, we give an overview over the highlights of this version.
Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementing the new features of RCE 9.0 required significant changes to the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We recently released RCE 9.0, which includes new features as well as improvements to existing ones.
In the following, we give an overview over the highlights of this version.
Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementing the new features of RCE 9.0 required significant changes to the way the user profiles are stored.
Hence, depending on your configuration, some manual steps may be necessary when upgrading existing profiles.
If you would like to reinstate these settings, please consult the &lt;a href="pages/documentation/migration-guide.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Migration Guide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
Moreover, the same changes required raising the minimal required Java version to Java 8u161.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Authorization System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RCE now features a fine-grained publication system that allows granting access to published tools only to certain users.
While previously, a published tool was accessible to all instances in the same RCE network, users can now create so-called "Authorization Groups" and restrict access to a published tool to members of certain groups.
Moreover, tools can be assigned to the pre-defined "public" group, which models the old behavior of making a tool accessible to every visible RCE instance.
The Authorization Groups are managed via the new Component Publishing view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://rcenvironment.de/images/release-9.0.0/authorization.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enhanced Remote Access via SSH&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have significantly improved the capabilities of SSH connections between RCE instances.
Previously, only tools and workflows that satisfied strict requirements towards their inputs and outputs could be published via SSH.
With this new release, these requirements are dropped and all tools that are published in the "public" group (see "New Authorization System" above) are accessible via SSH.
Moreover, it is possible to publish arbitrary workflows via SSH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, SSH connections now support accessing tool documentation and automatically reconnect when a previously interrupted connection becomes available again.
Finally, canceling a workflow now also cancels all currently running remote tools that are accessed via SSH connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Command Line Commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have implemented the new commands &lt;code&gt;wf details&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;wf open&lt;/code&gt; to further inspect the execution of a workflow from the command line, e.g., when running RCE in headless mode or accessing an instance via SSH.
The command &lt;code&gt;wf details&lt;/code&gt; lists detailed statistics for a workflow execution including its current status, the workflow controller used, and the number of executions of each component.
When using the RCE GUI, the workflow execution can also be inspected via the command &lt;code&gt;wf open&lt;/code&gt;, which opens a graphical view displaying the number of executions and the current state of each component.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, we have implemented the commands &lt;code&gt;auth&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;auth create&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;auth delete&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;auth import&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;auth export&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;auth list&lt;/code&gt; to manage the creation and distribution of Authorization Groups (see ''New Authorization System'' above). For more information on these new commands, please refer to the &lt;a href="pages/documentation/documentation.html"&gt;user guide&lt;/a&gt; or the built-in help system of the command console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://rcenvironment.de/images/release-9.0.0/wfdetails.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Naming Rules for Tools, Versions, and Group Names&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to improve cross-platform support for tools and to simplify internal handling, we have added strict validation of tool names and versions as well as group names. Existing tools that violate these rules are automatically deactivated and have to be activated before becoming available again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Robustness Against Network Outages and High CPU Load&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In previous versions of RCE, all systems running any component of a distributed workflow had to be available both at the start of the workflow as well as during the whole duration of the workflow execution.
Otherwise, i.e., if any machine involved became unavailable or unresponsive at any point during the execution of the workflow, the whole execution was canceled.
With RCE 9.0, this is no longer the case:
The workflow controller now waits for temporarily unavailable machines to reconnect or recover.
Hence, the workflow execution can recover from temporary network disruptions and periods of high CPU load while executing workflow components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see the &lt;a href="pages/documentation/migration-guide.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Migration Guide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for documentation about profile migration to RCE 9.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>RCE 8.2.4</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/rce-824.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-12-04T14:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-12-04T14:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2018-12-04:/rce-824.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;RCE 8.2.4 is out now. Unfortunately, as part of the security improvements in 8.2.3, a bug regarding long filenames slipped in. This is fixed in this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-8.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;RCE 8.2.4 is out now. Unfortunately, as part of the security improvements in 8.2.3, a bug regarding long filenames slipped in. This is fixed in this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-8.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>RCE 8.2.3</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/rce-823.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-15T16:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-11-15T16:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2018-11-15:/rce-823.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have just released RCE 8.2.3. It adresses several security issues and significantly reduces the RAM usage of workflow and component hosts. Furthermore, network timeouts in complex workflows during the initialization phase are prevented and we have fixed an issue which did not allow to cancel a workflow …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have just released RCE 8.2.3. It adresses several security issues and significantly reduces the RAM usage of workflow and component hosts. Furthermore, network timeouts in complex workflows during the initialization phase are prevented and we have fixed an issue which did not allow to cancel a workflow during this phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-8.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>RCE 8.2.2</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/rce-822.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-30T14:15:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-30T14:15:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2018-05-30:/rce-822.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;RCE 8.2.2 has been released that fixes an SSH connection issue that occurs due to changes in Java version 8u161.
Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-8.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;RCE 8.2.2 has been released that fixes an SSH connection issue that occurs due to changes in Java version 8u161.
Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-8.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>RCE 8.2.1</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/rce-821.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-24T14:15:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-24T14:15:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2018-05-24:/rce-821.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;RCE 8.2.1 has been released and comes with some improvements and fixes.
Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-8.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Synopsis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug in the Optimizer component when using bounds of data type Vector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor internal fixes and improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;RCE 8.2.1 has been released and comes with some improvements and fixes.
Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-8.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Synopsis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug in the Optimizer component when using bounds of data type Vector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor internal fixes and improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>RCE 8.2</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/rce-82.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-02-02T10:15:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-02-02T10:15:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2018-02-02:/rce-82.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;RCE 8.2 is out now. We realized various new features and improvements. Here we present a selection.
Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-8.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;XML Values&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this release we added a new workflow component: XML Values. This component allows you to easily access the content of XML files …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;RCE 8.2 is out now. We realized various new features and improvements. Here we present a selection.
Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-8.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;XML Values&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this release we added a new workflow component: XML Values. This component allows you to easily access the content of XML files. Values can be inserted into a file or extracted from a file using the XPath notation as known from other components in RCE. Moreover the XPath chooser dialog was enhanced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://rcenvironment.de/images/release-8.2.0/xmlValues.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Exporting directly to projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a usability improvement we made it easier to export your data directly into projects. This comes into effect in the export of simulation results from the Workflow Data Browser and when writing data via the Output Writer component.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>RCE 8.1.1</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/rce-811.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-11-17T12:15:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-11-17T12:15:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2017-11-17:/rce-811.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We recently released RCE 8.1.1. It contains several bugfixes and minor improvements. Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-8.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Synopsis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal improvements to enhance building RCE as external developer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed some bugs regarding fault tolerant loops, SSH remote access and CPACS tool integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several minor fixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We recently released RCE 8.1.1. It contains several bugfixes and minor improvements. Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-8.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Synopsis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal improvements to enhance building RCE as external developer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed some bugs regarding fault tolerant loops, SSH remote access and CPACS tool integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several minor fixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>RCE 8.1</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/rce-81.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-14T13:53:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-07-14T13:53:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2017-07-14:/rce-81.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We just released RCE 8.1, which contains several new features and improvements. Here we present a selection of new features. Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-8.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Workflow Editor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In RCE 8.1, bidirectional connections between components are now depicted by separate connection lines, which allows a better overview …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We just released RCE 8.1, which contains several new features and improvements. Here we present a selection of new features. Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-8.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Workflow Editor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In RCE 8.1, bidirectional connections between components are now depicted by separate connection lines, which allows a better overview over the workflow. Also we enhanced the zooming capabilities of the workflow editor and added the capability to export workflows as images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://rcenvironment.de/images/release-8.1.0/bidirectional_connections.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enhanced Workflow Components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made enhancements to several workflow components: 
For all driver componennt, start values can be declared as constant. In the DOE Component, it is now possible to define a custom table as start input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Startup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We added a dialog for selecting the profile to start RCE with. Furthermore we reduced the disk activity on startup to allow a more efficient start of RCE.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>RCE 8.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/rce-80.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-06T13:19:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-12-06T13:19:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2016-12-06:/rce-80.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are proud to announce a new major release: RCE 8 - Red Snapper. It contains several new features and many improvements. Below is a selection of some of them. Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-8.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Manual Verification of Tool Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In collaborative workflows, the tools involved are contributed by …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are proud to announce a new major release: RCE 8 - Red Snapper. It contains several new features and many improvements. Below is a selection of some of them. Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-8.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Manual Verification of Tool Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In collaborative workflows, the tools involved are contributed by different persons and usually run at different sites within one organization or even accross multiple organizations. Tool results are passed from one tool to all succeeding ones. In a collaborative setup, one want to avoid passing wrong tool results to tools that belong to another person in order to avoid a waste of compute resources at another site. To allow a tool integrator to check tool results before they are passed to another tool, we have introduced the concept of manual verification of tool results. If enabled, the tool results are only passed to other tools if the tool integrator has approved them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://rcenvironment.de/images/release-8.0.0/result_verification.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enhanced Workflow Editor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to prevent overlapping of small elements by larger ones, we have added a z-index ordering for workflow components and labels. Workflow labels can have a header now and we added automatic word wrap. If a workflow file is opened from the workflow data browser a read-only version of the workflow editor is opened now. It allows the comprehension of the workflow and the component configurations without the chance to modify it by mistake. Furthermore, enabling and disabling the so called 'Tool Run Imitation Mode' can be done with the help of the context menu now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://rcenvironment.de/images/release-8.0.0/read_only_editor.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enhanced Nested Loop Support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RCE is capable of running workflows with nested loops. The creation of nested loops got easier. An additional connection beetween the workflow driver components (indicating whether the loop is terminated) is not required anymore. Furthermore, for each input and output of workflow driver components the information is given whether they are supposed to be connected to the loop driven by this workflow driver component or to the next upper loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enhanced Workflow Components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have made several enhancements to workflow components such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evaluation memory component is nested-loop-capable now. We have added a validation for the python executable location given by the user at workflow start for Script components. The Design of Experiments component has a new output that provides the number of design sets going to be sent.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>RCE 7.1</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/rce-71.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-24T15:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-05-24T15:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2016-05-24:/rce-71.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We recently released RCE 7.1, a new minor version with several new features and many improvements. Below is a selection of some features. Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-7.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Unified Access to Documentation in RCE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation of RCE is spread over different places: component documentation is accessible from …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We recently released RCE 7.1, a new minor version with several new features and many improvements. Below is a selection of some features. Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-7.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Unified Access to Documentation in RCE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation of RCE is spread over different places: component documentation is accessible from the workflow editor, documentation about tool integration is accessible from the tool integration dialog, and the user guide in PDF format. We introduced a new help system to make all of the documentation additionally accessible from one single place. Go to the menu bar under "Help -&amp;gt; Help Contents". A window opens with all of the documentation and nice navigation and search capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://rcenvironment.de/images/release-7.1/help_system.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Workflow Outline View&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workflows with many components get quite big. For keeping track of those workflows, we added a new outline view. It displays the complete workflow in a thumbnail format and highlights the area of the workflow which is currently shown in the workflow editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://rcenvironment.de/images/release-7.1/outline_view.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enhanced Workflow Canceling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case a workflow is canceled (by the user or after a failure in the workflow), integrated tools as well as running Python scripts (executed by the Script component) are canceled imediately. It is no longer waited until they terminate itself. Also, jobs submitted to a cluster (by the Cluster component) are canceled imediately. In case of long running tools, scripts or cluster jobs, compute time is saved now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://rcenvironment.de/images/release-7.1/canceled.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Extended SSH Remote Access&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RCE provides an SSH interface to execute components and workflows (among others). Next to username and password, authentication via key files is now supported. Also, when connecting an RCE client to another RCE instance via SSH, not only remotely published components can be used in workflows, but also remotely published workflows appear in the workflow component palette ready to use in workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enhanced Workflow Components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made enhancements to several workflow components such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mapping file required by the XML Merger can be sent as an input. This makes reloading the mapping file on each change obsolete.&lt;br&gt;
The Evaluation Memory can be used in fault-tolerant loops as it is now able to treat loop failures properly.
The behavior of the Converger can be defined in case convergence was not reached. Also, outputs are added which indicate convergence for every input separately.
The Output Writer supports new placeholders: "original filename" and "execution count".  &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>RCE 7</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/rce-7.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-01T15:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-12-01T15:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2015-12-01:/rce-7.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are proud to announce RCE 7. A major release with a lot of features and various improvements. Below you find a selection of some features. Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-7.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Remote Tool Access via SSH Connections&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To access and execute tools across untrusted networks, we added support …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are proud to announce RCE 7. A major release with a lot of features and various improvements. Below you find a selection of some features. Please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/rcenvironment/rce/wiki/Changelog:-7.x.x-Releases"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Remote Tool Access via SSH Connections&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To access and execute tools across untrusted networks, we added support for tool access and execution via SSH, a secure network protocol. Please note that otherwise RCE is intended to be used in trusted networks only. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://rcenvironment.de/images/release-7/ssh_connections.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passwords for SSH accounts are configured as non-recoverable ("hashed") format now. We added a special configuration interface for SSH accounts ("rce --configure"). To support editing SSH accounts on servers, this UI can also be run in text mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://rcenvironment.de/images/release-7/ssh-account_config.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enhanced Workflow Logging&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We reviewed and improved all of the workflow-related log messages. We made them more suitable for end users. A log file is stored for each workflow component. Additionally, a log file for each workflow is stored with all of the error log messages related to the workflow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://rcenvironment.de/images/release-7/workflow_logging.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enhanced Workflow Examples&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We reworked the workflow examples so that they function as a kind of tutorial now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://rcenvironment.de/images/release-7/workflow_examples.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Workflow Components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We added two new workflow components. The 'Database' workflow component supports select, insert, update, and delete statements for MySQL and PostgreSQL databases. The 'Evaluation Memory' workflow component stores evaluation results of workflows for later re-use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://rcenvironment.de/images/release-7/new_workflow_components.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;System Monitoring for RCE Instances&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We added support for system monitoring. Information about CPU and RAM usage are provided: for the host system, for RCE itself, and for each each tool that is executed by RCE. The information can even be accessed for remote RCE instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://rcenvironment.de/images/release-7/system_monitoring_and_ssh.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 6.3.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-630.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-29T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-07-29T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2015-07-29:/release-630.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Synopsis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This release fixes a security issue; users that run components on untrusted machines should upgrade to 6.3.0 as soon as possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various minor bugfixes and improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflow Data Browser: Added icons to the top-level workflow entries that show the final state of workflows &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XML Merger: Added …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Synopsis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This release fixes a security issue; users that run components on untrusted machines should upgrade to 6.3.0 as soon as possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various minor bugfixes and improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflow Data Browser: Added icons to the top-level workflow entries that show the final state of workflows &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XML Merger: Added input handling "queue" to static input "XML to integrate"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design of Experiments: Improved cleanup of temp directories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design of Experiments: The component can now be used in outer loops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design of Experiments: Improved validation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Input Provider: Fixed selection of files and folders in imported projects or projects located outside the workspace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPACS Writer: Improved cleanup of temp directories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Workflow Data Browser&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added icons to the top-level workflow entries that show the final state of finished workflows; running workflows keep the default workflow icon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed saving of execution log files in case of an error&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed working directory to be shown for CPACS components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tool Integration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a file containing the running workflow's name to the working directory of tools ("rce-workflow-information.txt")&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed "Run only on changed inputs" option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed path for directory inputs when using placeholder variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This release fixes a security issue; users that run components on untrusted machines should upgrade to 6.3.0 as soon as possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Console Commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The output of "wf run" now includes the workflow id needed for other commands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a &lt;code&gt;"--compact-output"&lt;/code&gt; flag to "wf run" to simplify scripted usage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Remote Access&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made a minor protocol change that allows consistent behavior for Debian 7 clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Internal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased the heap size setting for RCE instances running on 32-bit Java by 20%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various minor bugfixes and improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced debug log output volume to make it easier to inspect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 6.2.1</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-621.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-24T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-06-24T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2015-06-24:/release-621.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Synopsis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed broken directory structure for files and directories, which are received as input values by the script component and by integrated tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed reliably XSLT mapping files from working directories of integrated CPACS tools (in some cases they are left)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endpoints can be deleted again even if they are …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Synopsis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed broken directory structure for files and directories, which are received as input values by the script component and by integrated tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed reliably XSLT mapping files from working directories of integrated CPACS tools (in some cases they are left)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endpoints can be deleted again even if they are currently connected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Due to some issues, the renaming option for files and directories received by integrated tools is removed (it is always "-As incoming-" now) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 6.2.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-620.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-12T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-06-12T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2015-06-12:/release-620.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Synopsis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved usability of various graphical user elements including log messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extended and improved the access of tools and workflows via SSH (remote access)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed minor bugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal improvements (e.g., improved quality assurance by increasing unit test coverage) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Usability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Script component&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Files and directories (received as input values) keep …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Synopsis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved usability of various graphical user elements including log messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extended and improved the access of tools and workflows via SSH (remote access)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed minor bugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal improvements (e.g., improved quality assurance by increasing unit test coverage) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Usability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Script component&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Files and directories (received as input values) keep their name (affects e.g. the name shown in the workflow data browser)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support to show whitespace characters in the text field used to write the Python script &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tool integration dialog&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for editing values (inputs, outputs, properties etc.) on double click&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added dialog which helps to create Python commands to copy files or directories within the pre or post execution script &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflow data browser&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The host instance of each workflow component is now shown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added possibility to open CPACS files in the TiGL viewer from the workflow data browser's context menu &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflow list&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflows can be deleted now with the Del key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed default sorting (now by time) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Command console: added feature to clear command console line on Esc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflow console: added possibility to copy either a whole console line or just the message itself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Announce syntax errors in the main configuration file of RCE at start up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflow execution&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved warning shown in the workflow execution dialog if workflow components are not available or only available with other versions (which prevents the user from executing a workflow at all)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved warning when component versions of workflow file and current installation don't match&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the new placeholders "${profileName}" and "${version}" to instance name configuration; this is intended to simplify deployments with many instances &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Remote Access (access of tools and workflows via SSH)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflows published with the "ra-admin publish-wf" command are now persistent by default (ie, they are still available after restarting the RCE instance)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tools on the RCE instance running the SSH server must now be explicitly published to be available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clients can now explicitly select the instance of a tool that is available on multiple RCE instances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filtered the "list-tools" output to tools that actually match the Remote Access requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The client's tool selection is now checked against the published/available tools before execution; before this, invalid values simply caused the generated workflow to fail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved error handling and feedback messages &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bug Fixes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joiner component: fixed the configuration GUI of the joiner component so that its elements are applied correctly after undo or redo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Command console: Fixed pasting from clipboard into the command console on linux systems (fixed delay and issue with line break)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed writing integer values to outputs of type float in script component and post script of integrated tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflow data browser: fixed exporting directories from the workflow data browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Files and projects can be deleted from workspace projects now even if they were opened beforehand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflow editor: workflow components, which are not available, can be now copied/cutted and pasted as they were be available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed resource leaks in workflow data browser and workflow timeline view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflow engine: constant inputs of loop driver components (e.g. Optimizer, DOE, ... ) are now reset if loop was reset (mainly affects loop drivers of nested loops) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Internal Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved quality assurance by increasing unit test coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactor the code base responsible for loading, mapping, and saving XML files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 6.1.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-610.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-16T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-04-16T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2015-04-16:/release-610.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Workflow Components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new component: Switch &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Directs data on the base of a condition to one of two outputs &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new component: Design of Experiments (DOE) &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports sampling of a bounded solution space &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Converger: Replaced "maximum iterations" by "maximum convergence checks" &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parametric Study: Added option "fit to bounds"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimizer &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Workflow Components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new component: Switch &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Directs data on the base of a condition to one of two outputs &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new component: Design of Experiments (DOE) &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports sampling of a bounded solution space &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Converger: Replaced "maximum iterations" by "maximum convergence checks" &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parametric Study: Added option "fit to bounds"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimizer &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for mixed integer optimization &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated new algorithm method called NOMAD, which is more applicable for mixed integer optimization &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tool Integration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extended options for the deletion of working directories: they can be kept in the case of an error now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pre and post processing scripts now have the "shutil" module imported by default to simplify file and directory copying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enabled tabbing through the "Tool Description" page of the tool integration wizard &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Workflow Editor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added possibility to define custom connection paths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for workflow labels &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Workflow Data Browser&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved performance when fetching the list of workflows and when expanding timelines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an error in the graphical tree view which sometimes occured when deleting workflows ("Comparison method violates contract")&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an error which allowed running workflows to be deleted under certain circumstances &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Workflow Data Management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved stability and performance (especially for workflows with a high number of component runs - in the order of &amp;gt;10,000 runs) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;GUI Miscellaneous&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the performance of the workflow list view (workflows and their states were updated very slowly from remote workflow hosts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the font (Courier) for the command console and script editing areas (the Script component's editor and the tool integration wizard's pre and post processing pages)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed layout of the input table of the OutputWriter component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validation of workflow components' configuration is now only done when saving the workflow; this improves GUI performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validation errors and/or warnings are now checked at workflow start again and are shown to the user with a popup dialog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflow execution wizards shows the actual instance names as they appear in the network view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The "Apply to all" button in the placeholder page of the workflow execution wizard copies the placeholder only to other placeholders of the same data type and the same component type now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the insert locations of pasted workflow nodes; prevented the case where inserted components have the same position, which made them hard to tell apart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connection Editor: Inputs which are required but not connected yet are marked with a red asterisk &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Remote Access&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a command to only list components that are compatible with the "run-tool" requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made command output easier to parse by client code (used by upcoming C/C++ API)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a default version ("1") to published workflows so "run-wf" and "run-tool" can use the same API calls &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Console Commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added console commands to pause, resume, cancel, and dispose workflows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added console command to list all active workflows (wf list) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Configuration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the embedded SSH server's "host" parameter to "ip" for clarity ("host" still works, but a warning is logged)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed some configuration documentation issues &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deployment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provided 32-bit .deb packages (in addition to existing 64-bit packages) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added documentation for concept behind the CPACS mapping of integrated CPACS-capable tools &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;CPACS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated namespace for map in cpacs mapping files (old one still works, but a warning is logged) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disabled the "&lt;profile&gt;/output/console.combined.*.log" files to conserve disk space; if you were using them, please contact us for discussion of this feature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed irrelevant stack traces to reduce log volume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved log output of network error situations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added "--profile" option as an alternative/alias to "-p"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the profile directory's name not being used for the temp directory prefix (was always "default")&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cleaned up the command console's "help" output&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Script component (Jython) now sends unique NaV values to the affected outputs within one run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A workflow component, which triggers that a workflow is finished, doesn't forward the finish information anymore (this led to warnings in the log)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced callback attempts of a workflow component if its workflow controller is not reachable anymore; reduced number of error messages in the log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased the automated test coverage (especially, workflow engine, data management, workflow components)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generation of "Output/autoExportOnStartup.json" is now optional (default: off) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 6.0.3</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-603.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-02-03T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-02-03T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2015-02-03:/release-603.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced heap size (declared in rce.ini) for Windows 32bit version of RCE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added configuration parameter for RCE profiles to the windows service installation script &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced heap size (declared in rce.ini) for Windows 32bit version of RCE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added configuration parameter for RCE profiles to the windows service installation script &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 6.0.2</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-602.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-01-28T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-01-28T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2015-01-28:/release-602.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed tool integration wizard, which failed to integrate a tool under some certain circumstances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Converger and optimizer component sent value, whether the loop was converged/optimized on each iteration again (In 6.0.0 and 6.0.1, it was sent only once at the end as loop was converged …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed tool integration wizard, which failed to integrate a tool under some certain circumstances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Converger and optimizer component sent value, whether the loop was converged/optimized on each iteration again (In 6.0.0 and 6.0.1, it was sent only once at the end as loop was converged/optimized) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 6.0.1</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-601.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-01-22T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-01-22T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2015-01-22:/release-601.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed scheduling of script component - problem occured if it was enabled, that the script component should run on each new input value &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed scheduling of script component - problem occured if it was enabled, that the script component should run on each new input value &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 6.0.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-600.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-01-15T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-01-15T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2015-01-15:/release-600.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Workflow Editor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Components in a workflow can now be temporarily disabled: during workflow execution, these components and all their connections are treated as if they didn't exist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added an option to show the number of connections represented by a line between two components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The connection editor dialog can now be …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Workflow Editor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Components in a workflow can now be temporarily disabled: during workflow execution, these components and all their connections are treated as if they didn't exist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added an option to show the number of connections represented by a line between two components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The connection editor dialog can now be opened by double-clicking a connection line, too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added shortcuts for "Draw Connection" mode (ALT + D) and "Selection" mode (ALT + S) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Connection Editor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved handling of workflows with many connections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inputs which are already connected to an output are now marked by a small arrow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added more filtering options for inputs and outputs (match exactly, start with, contain) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Workflow List&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pause/Resume/Cancel/Dispose can now be applied to multiple workflows at once &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Timeline GUI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new feature that visualizes when each component was running during workflow execution &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Configuration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merged all previous configuration files (*.json) into a single file (configuration.json)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added option to open and edit this configuration file within the GUI (Help -&amp;gt; Open Configuration File)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made example configurations and path information accessible from the GUI (Help -&amp;gt; Open Configuration Information)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moved example configuration files to the easier-to-find "examples/configuration" folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The "instanceName" configuration entry now supports the placeholders ${systemUser} and ${hostName} for better default naming of RCE instances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added "connectOnStartup" option to network connections; the old behavior was to always connect when RCE starts, which is now optional &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Multi-User Support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added full support for multi-user operation, i.e. one RCE installation can be used by multiple users on the same system; the RCE installation directory can be set to "read-only" for all users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for multiple profiles per user, each with its own configuration, log files, and data storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Linux, temporary file directories are now automatically separated (/tmp/rce-temp-&lt;user id&gt;) to prevent file ownership and permission problems; when customizing this path, the placeholder ${systemUser} is available &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installation and Release Signing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provided .deb packages for Debian/Ubuntu/Mint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provided .rpm packages for CentOS/Red Hat/SUSE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provided a signed APT repository for Linux Debian/Ubuntu/Mint which allows installation via "apt-get" or package managers with GUI (e.g. Synaptic), as well as full integration with automatic system updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All .zip, .deb, and .rpm release packages now have digitally signed checksum files (SHA256SUMS.asc) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Linux Support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completely reworked (and simplified) Linux daemon installation and handling ("rce-daemon" command)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved Linux distribution compatibility; RCE is now regularly tested on Debian 7, SUSE 11 SP 2, and CentOS 7 (all 64 bit); it is also confirmed to run on Ubuntu 12 LTS, Ubuntu 14 LTS, Mint 17, and Red Hat Enterprise 6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added standard Linux desktop integration (application icon and basic menu entry) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Remote Tool/Workflow Access&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a Remote Workflow Access template, which can also be used for out-of-the box testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplified the handling of input and output directories; when accessing them from script code, no additional sub-directory levels ("/input/") are required anymore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moved example script files to the easier-to-find "examples/remote_access" folder &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Optimizer Component&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added an output that indicates whether gradients are requested by the optimizer method within the current iteration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated integrated Dakota version from 5.1 to 6.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Dakota methods: SOGA, MOGA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for using precalculation files (reset files)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for failure-tolerant optimization loops (see Section "Workflow Engine" below) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Script API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various improvements and extensions (e.g. support for "not a value", execution count, persistent state)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added option to close the outputs of tools in pre/postprocessing scripts of tool integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed deprecated parts of the API &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tool Integration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made the script API accessible in pre/postprocessing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added an option to limit the number of parallel tool executions (e.g. to prevent excessive license usage) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Data Management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Major rework of the data management backend (data model and API) to increase performance and robustness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflow Data Browser now shows input and output data of all components and additional workflow run information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflow Data Browser now also shows the path to the working directories of integrated tools (for manual inspection) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Usability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplified resetting the "Don't ask again" setting of the workspace chooser. It can be reset via "Help -&amp;gt; Open Configuration Information". &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Batch mode (rce --batch)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Command execution output is now written to standard output as well, which makes it available from the invoking command line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved robustness &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Workflow Engine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completely reworked workflow execution (as a prerequisite for single component run, restart after failure, and stepwise execution)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reworked scheduling options (initial, required, optional -&amp;gt; constant, single, consumed and required, required if connected, not required). For details and migration path, see documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provided better support for nested loops including reset of nested loops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made optimization and parametric study loops failure-tolerant, i.e. extended Python/Jython script API to allow to indicate that tool/script failed, but only because of invalid input parameters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added automatic writing of basic history data (inputs, outputs) to all components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed workflow console row writer to ensure no log rows are missing after workflow execution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added handling of system time differences between workflow controller and component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added handling of system time differences between workflow controller and component hosts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for limitation of parallel tool executions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cluster&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for TORQUE 5.0 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Converger&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added possiblity to finish on first check for negative values &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added "–dispose" flag to "wf run" command to allow disposal after workflow execution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added "–dispose", "–pr" and "–sr" flags to "wf verify" command (for automated testing) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other/Misc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merged the three former RCE editions (Standard/CPACS/Transport) into a single one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved branding (splash screen, about dialog, ...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgraded to Eclipse RCP 3.7.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the cleanup mechanism for temporary files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On RCE startup, the last debug.log and warnings.log files are automatically preserved as *.previous.log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various bugfixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various usability tweaks &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 5.2.1</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-521.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-29T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-08-29T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2014-08-29:/release-521.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed error when integrating a tool using a template of type 'Common' &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed error when integrating a tool using a template of type 'Common' &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 5.2.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-520.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-25T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-08-25T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2014-08-25:/release-520.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;General&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved clean up of RCE's temp directory &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;GUI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General performance improvement in workflow data browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed handling of scripts that were openend in an editor at the same time and that belong to different script components &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Workflow components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimizer component&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved behavior if optimizer fails or isn't available at …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;General&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved clean up of RCE's temp directory &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;GUI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General performance improvement in workflow data browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed handling of scripts that were openend in an editor at the same time and that belong to different script components &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Workflow components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimizer component&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved behavior if optimizer fails or isn't available at all &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Script component&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved error handling if non-existing files are written to an output &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tool integration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug using boolean values in pre/post script&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for relative paths to the tool directory (relative to the RCE installation directory) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Network&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where many crashed connections could cause a high number of remaining threads and could also cause a memory leak &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Headless RCE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new command for batch execution. It executes a set of commands and shuts down RCE no matter what: --batch &lt;command string&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for placeholder values on component instance base (and not only on component type base)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved fault tolerance when execution a workflow in batch mode and not all of the required remote nodes exists immediately on start up because of network latency (but will be available directly after start up) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved documentation of string security filter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added documentation for placeholder value files used in headless mode &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 5.1.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-510.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-25T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-07-25T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2014-07-25:/release-510.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;GUI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a view to execute RCE console commands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added miscellaneous context menu entries for faster access to key features (such as integrating a new tool or creating the workflow examples project)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed short cut for renaming workflow nodes (it is just F2 now)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved visibility of self-connections of components …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;GUI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a view to execute RCE console commands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added miscellaneous context menu entries for faster access to key features (such as integrating a new tool or creating the workflow examples project)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed short cut for renaming workflow nodes (it is just F2 now)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved visibility of self-connections of components in the workflow editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Component names are shortened from the center if the entire name is too long to fit in the workflow node box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Further improved the GUI's responsiveness, especially when RCE is connected to remote instances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Placeholders (such as Python installation path, cluster component credentials) are not shared between copied workflow files anymore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various bug fixes &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Workflow components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cluster component &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Absolute paths to the cluster queuing system commands are now configurable &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for indicating failed cluster jobs &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Converger component &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The number of iterations to consider in the convergence check is now configurable (not only the current and previous, but the current and n previous values can be considered now)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimizer component  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starts dispatching initial design variable values for evaluation not before it gets the first explicit evaluation request from the optimization algorithm &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tool integration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tools can be published and unpublished on the file-system level without restarting RCE (especially useful for non-GUI server nodes) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miscellaneous improvements &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Command interface&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The "wf run" command can now be used to run workflow files containing placeholders (Python path etc.) as well; this is done by specifying a JSON file containing the required placeholder values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the "wf verify" command for batch testing of workflow files; placeholder files are supported as with the "wf run" command &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Administration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When installing RCE as a Linux daemon, the RCE instance can now be run as a non-root user (which is highly recommended); note that the installation process still requires root permissions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a startup check to detect missing temporary folder permissions early &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Network&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Active connection attempts can now be cancelled by pressing "stop/disconnect" in the Network View, or by using the "cn stop" console command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Failed connections waiting to auto-reconnect can now be made to reconnect immediately (without stopping them first) by pressing "start/connect" in the Network View, or by using the "cn stop" console command &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Remote access / Tool Access&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In addition to the remote execution of single tools, complete workflows can now be invoked through the SSH/SCP interface &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added contextual help for all workflow components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed the standard Eclipse platform's help content from the integrated help center and replaced it with information about RCE's user guide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extended the user guide with help for integrating tools in RCE &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 5.0.2</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-502.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-26T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-06-26T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2014-06-26:/release-502.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some fixes regarding the optimizer component &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor fixes &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some fixes regarding the optimizer component &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor fixes &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 5.0.1</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-501.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-12T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-06-12T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2014-06-12:/release-501.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some fixes regarding the deletion of workflows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some fixes regarding connections (auto-connect, copy&amp;amp;paste, ...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provided dynamic help in script component again &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some fixes regarding the deletion of workflows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some fixes regarding connections (auto-connect, copy&amp;amp;paste, ...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provided dynamic help in script component again &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 5.0.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-500.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-15T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-05-15T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2014-05-15:/release-500.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Workflow components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added an "Output Writer" component to write directories and files to the local file system &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimizer&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iteration count is now available as an output&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for the Vector data type (to support multiple (hundreds) of design variables)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for start values and optimal solution outputs …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Workflow components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added an "Output Writer" component to write directories and files to the local file system &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimizer&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iteration count is now available as an output&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for the Vector data type (to support multiple (hundreds) of design variables)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for start values and optimal solution outputs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gradients variables can be set as goals in Dakota&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for nested loops &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Script&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for Vector and Matrix data types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for history data (shown in the workflow data browser)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed memory leaks related to frequent script execution &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tool integration&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for history data (shown in the workflow data browser)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for hot deployment of configuration.json files (i.e., if a new tool configuration is dropped at the proper place, the tool will be considered and integrated immediately without any further user interaction. Especially useful for RCE server instances without a GUI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfix: All console output is now properly separated in the workflow console view &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renamed component: Merger -&amp;gt; Joiner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaced/improved some component icons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplified the identifiers of components (the ones which are used in the .json files to configure which of the components are published)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the ToolAccess interface that allows external (non-RCE) clients to execute integrated tools via SSH/SCP &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various bugfixes and performance improvements &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;GUI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the responsivness of the graphical user interface, especially in distributed setups under high load&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflow editor&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connections are now properly handled when workflow nodes are copied and pasted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduced different sizes and shapes for workflow components in the editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed the "Advanced" configuration tab as it is not intended (and therefore confusing) for end users
    Added support for a "point&amp;amp;click" method to connect component's endpoints (in addition to the existing "drag&amp;amp;drop" method) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflow data browser&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The storage location of history data is now visible in the browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Component history entries now use the component's icon for easier recognition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sorting is now context sensitive (e.g., no support for alphabetical sortinng in timeline subtree)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When exporting, all history data is now properly fetched recursively, even if it was not made visible before&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated the internal history data format for better long-term stability &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the iteration counter for components in the workflow execution view &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various graphical user interface improvements &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added information about supported operating systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added information about the scheduling parameters: required, initial, optional&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added documentation of the ToolAccess feature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General improvements &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Configuration and administration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switched to Java 7 (i.e., Java 7 or higher is required to execute RCE 5.0.0 and above)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a separate log file that only lists warnings and errors (warnings.log)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The location of the instance data directory (including the data management's storage) can now be freely configured; it is no longer restricted to be inside "&lt;user home&gt;/.rce" &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 4.2.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-420.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-02-07T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-02-07T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2014-02-07:/release-420.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added documentation for user and developer (see new documentation folder)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;implemented IP whitelisting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;implemented automatic network reconnect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;made upload block size configurable (see user guide)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added service/daemon scripts including installation scripts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General tweaks and bugfixes &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added documentation for user and developer (see new documentation folder)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;implemented IP whitelisting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;implemented automatic network reconnect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;made upload block size configurable (see user guide)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added service/daemon scripts including installation scripts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General tweaks and bugfixes &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 4.1.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-410.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-12-20T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-12-20T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2013-12-20:/release-410.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Component connections can now be directly selected and deleted in the workflow editor (required using the connection dialog before)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved automatic behaviour when connecting components in the editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved handling of special cases in data management browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running RCE instances can now be shutdown by running the executable again with …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Component connections can now be directly selected and deleted in the workflow editor (required using the connection dialog before)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved automatic behaviour when connecting components in the editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved handling of special cases in data management browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running RCE instances can now be shutdown by running the executable again with the --shutdown flag (supports installation of RCE as a system service)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added "tool access" feature that allows remote execution of user-integrated tools via SSH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved SSH command interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renamed embedded SSH server configuration file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General tweaks and bugfixes &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 4.0.1</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-401.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-12-04T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-12-04T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2013-12-04:/release-401.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed two issues missed in release testing&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restored configuration tabs for deprecated Simple Wrapper component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restored context help for workflow components &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed two issues missed in release testing&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restored configuration tabs for deprecated Simple Wrapper component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restored context help for workflow components &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 4.0.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-400.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-11-29T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-11-29T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2013-11-29:/release-400.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;GUI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a wizard to simplify the creation of new workflows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extended Network view&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflow components are shown per node (for own node: locally installed and published ones; for remote nodes: published ones)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connections to other nodes are shown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connections to others can be managed (added, edited, deleted, started, stopped …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;GUI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a wizard to simplify the creation of new workflows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extended Network view&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflow components are shown per node (for own node: locally installed and published ones; for remote nodes: published ones)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connections to other nodes are shown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connections to others can be managed (added, edited, deleted, started, stopped) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issues regarding copy&amp;amp;paste of workflow components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed result view of Parametric Study component when it is opened multiple times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved responsiveness of the graphical user interface by reworking long-lasting operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General improvements&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix configuration validation in Script component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added additional context menus where applicable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed tool bar icons for workflow control as they didn't work reliably; may be added again in a future version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed unnecessary menu entries in the graphical user interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added button in placeholder page (in workflow execution wizard) to select a file from the file system if the placeholder represents a file system path&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added menu entry to switch between workspaces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added menu entry to restart RCE &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Workflow Components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added generic integration concept to integrate tools as workflow components&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tools are integrated using a graphical wizard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Newly integrated tools can immediately be made available ("published") to other users &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed constraints handling in Optimizer component for Dakota algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made Converger component more robust against inputs that are received after convergence of component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restricted input types of Parametric Study component to floating point numbers and integers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If script in Script component reads an input that is optional or required and which has no new value, an exception is thrown now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reworked Cluster component: inputs and outputs are directories, and multiple jobs can be submitted within one iteration &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Workflow Engine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new data type "Directory"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reworked the way how values/data are sent from one workflow component to another to improve performance and adapt to the new multi-network feature (see below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marked workflow components as deprecated if they are intended to be removed in future versions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When workflow components (without result views) are finished, the hosting RCE node can now be shut down without breaking the workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a memory leak that occurred during workflow component execution &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Communication Layer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RCE nodes can now connect to multiple networks without creating a connection between them; previously, this caused all networks to merge into a single, larger network. The new behaviour gives network administrators better control of computing resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made network connections restartable (usable from Network View and command shell)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provided infrastructure for more efficient distribution of node information (for example, the list of published components)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved handling of routing information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved routing performance by reducing the number of re-calculations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a server-side resource leak in the ActiveMQ network transport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added first draft of an SSH administration console &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Others&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed unnecessary files in installation folder of RCE (launcher(.exe), eclipsec.exe)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved log messages (e.g. removed irrelevant stack traces, reviewed and reduced warnings)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"rce.log" is now located in the main directory (previously in "configuration")&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved internal event handling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shortened path length of temporary files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General tweaks, bugfixes and performance improvements &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 3.2.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-320.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-24T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2013-09-24T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2013-09-24:/release-320.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved handling of long-lasting remote component initializations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed validation errors not showing up in log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed connection removal via Undo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;workflows are properly disposed on shutdown now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved default workspace locations of "launch" configurations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed double-click in read-only workflow view switching to properties view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;changed behaviour of Script component …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved handling of long-lasting remote component initializations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed validation errors not showing up in log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed connection removal via Undo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;workflows are properly disposed on shutdown now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved default workspace locations of "launch" configurations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed double-click in read-only workflow view switching to properties view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;changed behaviour of Script component on second click&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated example workflows and fixed nested loop workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed sending an output to more than one input&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;guarded converger component against certain loop behavior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed handling of Boolean values in component input view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;existing workflows are now properly shown after a network merge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;workflow console output is now properly removed after workflow deletion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed remote workflow deletion breaking workflow tabs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed workflow console scrolling issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;made TiGLViewer a dedicated component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TiglViewer: fixed issue with workbench restart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimizer component: improved configuration GUI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python/Jython component: deprecated old script API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python/Jython component: using the same names for inputs and outputs is now allowed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python/Jython component: fixed hangs on long console output&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excel component: fixed pruning of output channel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minor usability improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved test code coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;various other bug fixes &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 3.1.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-310.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-08-27T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2013-08-27T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2013-08-27:/release-310.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug regarding boolean values sent within a workflow (workflow components always retrieved 'false' even the previous component sent 'true')&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for workflow control from within scripts executed with the Script component again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GUI misc: mark GUI elements red if validation error exists (instead of yellow which is …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug regarding boolean values sent within a workflow (workflow components always retrieved 'false' even the previous component sent 'true')&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for workflow control from within scripts executed with the Script component again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GUI misc: mark GUI elements red if validation error exists (instead of yellow which is meant for validation warnings)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;internal: added example workflow components demonstrating how to develop a RCE workflow component &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 3.0.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-300.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-08-02T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2013-08-02T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2013-08-02:/release-300.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for remote upload of large files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unified data types of input values and output values which are used by workflow components (Note: all workflow files created with RCE &amp;lt; 3.0.0 will be updated by RCE when opening them for the first time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replace the Python workflow …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for remote upload of large files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unified data types of input values and output values which are used by workflow components (Note: all workflow files created with RCE &amp;lt; 3.0.0 will be updated by RCE when opening them for the first time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replace the Python workflow component with a more generic Script workflow component which supports still Python and and latterly also Jython&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added check if two RCE instances are compatible to each other (connection between them will be refused if not compatible)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for maximum iteration count in Converger workflow component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced messages exchanged during workflow run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved GUI&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added icon in workflow runtime tab, which shows the current state of a workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed memory leak in tab showing the input values of running workflow components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reworked and improved most of the workflow component configuration GUIs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the workflow run editor: it only allows RCE nodes to be selected which has the workflow component with an exact matching version installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added check for invalid connections: if data type of one connection's endpoint (input/output) is changed it will be checked now if it is compatible with the data type of the other endpoint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made the GUI in general more responsive even if long running (remote) operations are performed in the underlying backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More minor improvements &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.5.2</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-252.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-06-21T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2013-06-21T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2013-06-21:/release-252.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed problem in Excel component: it occurred if the Excel component was run in a distributed scenario &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed problem in Excel component: it occurred if the Excel component was run in a distributed scenario &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.5.1</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-251.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-06-10T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2013-06-10T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2013-06-10:/release-251.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extended Converger component to add support for nested loops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added workflow status icons to workflow runtime tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for macros to Excel component's export function&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excel component exports to clipboard with Excel-like insertion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed copying a workflow component in the workflow editor (the copied component had the same …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extended Converger component to add support for nested loops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added workflow status icons to workflow runtime tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for macros to Excel component's export function&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excel component exports to clipboard with Excel-like insertion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed copying a workflow component in the workflow editor (the copied component had the same name as the orgin one)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug with runtime variables, which causes errors under some special circumstances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed some memory leaks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed start up validators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added validation to the workflow connection editor: it prohibts a connection between an input and more than one output (this would result in scheduling problems)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minor fixes &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.5.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-250.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-04-05T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2013-04-05T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2013-04-05:/release-250.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new component for submitting cluster jobs was added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Major rework of the optimizer component&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updating a pre 2.5.0 workflow file containing an optimizer component will remove all previous method configuration &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved workflow updater&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved logging for failing python component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved error handling in optimizer component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new component for submitting cluster jobs was added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Major rework of the optimizer component&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updating a pre 2.5.0 workflow file containing an optimizer component will remove all previous method configuration &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved workflow updater&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved logging for failing python component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved error handling in optimizer component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added data type array to merger component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;passphrases for runtime configurations are stored in secure storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minor GUI improvement and fixes &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.4.2</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-242.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-13T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-03-13T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2013-03-13:/release-242.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added new workflow component "Input Provider": user can define input values for other components, like text, numbers, or files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved workflow editor handling&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved support for short cuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed minor issues &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved logging of workflow status during execution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved workflow execution in batch mode&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enabled workflow execution …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added new workflow component "Input Provider": user can define input values for other components, like text, numbers, or files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved workflow editor handling&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved support for short cuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed minor issues &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved logging of workflow status during execution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved workflow execution in batch mode&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enabled workflow execution from the command line &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved error handling in Simple Wrapper component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reworked and extended RCE console commands (e.g., added one for version information) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.4.1</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-241.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-01-23T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-01-23T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2013-01-23:/release-241.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added boolean channeltype in Python component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added mechanism to support wildcard entries in publishedComponents configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added configuration for rce-tmp folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed various bugs in SimpleWrapper component (i.e. regarding the use of input channels in pre/post process)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug in converger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minor fixes and improvements &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added boolean channeltype in Python component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added mechanism to support wildcard entries in publishedComponents configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added configuration for rce-tmp folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed various bugs in SimpleWrapper component (i.e. regarding the use of input channels in pre/post process)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug in converger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minor fixes and improvements &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.4.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-240.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-12-17T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-12-17T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2012-12-17:/release-240.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Major rework of the network/communication system; changes include:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;significant performance improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simplified setup of ad-hoc networks; in typical use cases, clients only a single line of configuration to connect to a network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simplified handling of firewalled systems and subnets &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reduced supported languages to English to avoid language mixups …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Major rework of the network/communication system; changes include:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;significant performance improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simplified setup of ad-hoc networks; in typical use cases, clients only a single line of configuration to connect to a network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simplified handling of firewalled systems and subnets &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reduced supported languages to English to avoid language mixups with third-party software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added sample project with example workflows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved validation of Excel component configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved error handling in Python component if an unsupported Python installation was chosen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improvements in graphical user interface of RCE (zooming behavior, graph plotting in Optimizer and Parametric Study component, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cleaned up graphical user interface on very first start of RCE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed "Simple Wrapper" execution under Linux when using multi-line command configurations created on Windows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed handling of multiple arrays in Python component &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.3.8</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-238.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-11-13T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-11-13T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2012-11-13:/release-238.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add updating mechanism for workflow files containing at least one Python component (it is not upwards compatible)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug in Simple Wrapper component (occurred if used as first component within an workflow)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug in Python component regarding array inputs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug in SQL component regarding array inputs &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add updating mechanism for workflow files containing at least one Python component (it is not upwards compatible)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug in Simple Wrapper component (occurred if used as first component within an workflow)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug in Python component regarding array inputs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug in SQL component regarding array inputs &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.3.7</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-237.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-11-07T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-11-07T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2012-11-07:/release-237.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added new concept for sensitive workflow configuration values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;re-designed Excel workflow component for stability and usability purposes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for Optimizer component (Dakota) in Linux versions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added view for cluster job monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug in configuration GUI of Simple Wrapper component (occured only in Linux versions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug in …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added new concept for sensitive workflow configuration values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;re-designed Excel workflow component for stability and usability purposes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for Optimizer component (Dakota) in Linux versions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added view for cluster job monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug in configuration GUI of Simple Wrapper component (occured only in Linux versions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug in input inspection view, which caused the GUI to freeze&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added sorting in various component listings like workflow execution wizard, connection dialog, input inspection view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved temp file handling in worklfow components to use less memory &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.3.6</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-236.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-18T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2012-10-18T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2012-10-18:/release-236.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added option to create a workflow examples project (new -&amp;gt; other -&amp;gt; RCE)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed problems and inaccurate problem descriptions in optimizer component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed some gui issues in optimizer component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed minor issues &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added option to create a workflow examples project (new -&amp;gt; other -&amp;gt; RCE)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed problems and inaccurate problem descriptions in optimizer component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed some gui issues in optimizer component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed minor issues &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.3.5</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-235.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-13T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2012-09-13T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2012-09-13:/release-235.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug that caused an error in running a distributed workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug in merger component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug in merger and converger components gui&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;workflow data browser nodes can now be deleted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;removed context menu entries for sorting of entries in workflow data browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ixed minor issues &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug that caused an error in running a distributed workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug in merger component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed bug in merger and converger components gui&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;workflow data browser nodes can now be deleted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;removed context menu entries for sorting of entries in workflow data browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ixed minor issues &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.3.4</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-234.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-08-10T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2012-08-10T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2012-08-10:/release-234.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added Design of Experiments component (test state)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added sorting order for workflow data browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added toggle buttons for workflow data browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added default explaining script in python component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added storage for persistent settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;textfields for commands in sql and simplewrapper component now resize when view gets resized&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;connection lines …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added Design of Experiments component (test state)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added sorting order for workflow data browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added toggle buttons for workflow data browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added default explaining script in python component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added storage for persistent settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;textfields for commands in sql and simplewrapper component now resize when view gets resized&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;connection lines now use anti-aliasing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed minor issues &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.3.3</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-233.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-04T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2012-07-04T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2012-07-04:/release-233.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added Converger component (test state)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added Merger component (test state)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for compression data management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added filter for workflow components in connection editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for Coliny Cobyla algorithm in optimizer component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed input queue view showing pending inputs of components (shows input in wrong order if a …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added Converger component (test state)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added Merger component (test state)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for compression data management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added filter for workflow components in connection editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for Coliny Cobyla algorithm in optimizer component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed input queue view showing pending inputs of components (shows input in wrong order if a lot of inputs were sent within a short time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed deleting in- and output variables in Excel component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed minor issues &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.3.2</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-232.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-06-14T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2012-06-14T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2012-06-14:/release-232.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for RCE headless mode: workflow execution without GUI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added workspace chooser at RCE start up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved workflow scheduler logic: support of different input usages (required, initial, optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added compare function for text files in workflow data browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added "Reset search" button for workflow console filter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added "Save …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for RCE headless mode: workflow execution without GUI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added workspace chooser at RCE start up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved workflow scheduler logic: support of different input usages (required, initial, optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added compare function for text files in workflow data browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added "Reset search" button for workflow console filter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added "Save as ..." to 'File' menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extended start up validators: length of parent file system path, JVM settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed copying of workflow nodes: copied workflow node is a real new clone now. Thus, workflow nodes don't receive configuration values of other nodes anymore)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed minor issues &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.3.1</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-231.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-05-14T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2012-05-14T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2012-05-14:/release-231.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for sorting in workflow data management browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for data export to Excel in parametric study component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unified configuration tabs in parametric and optimizer runtime graphical user interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;restored "goal" option when editing variable in optimizer component configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed start up validator for JSON configuration files …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for sorting in workflow data management browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for data export to Excel in parametric study component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unified configuration tabs in parametric and optimizer runtime graphical user interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;restored "goal" option when editing variable in optimizer component configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed start up validator for JSON configuration files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed minor build infrastructure issues &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.3.0</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-230.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-04-19T10:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2012-04-19T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2012-04-19:/release-230.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added optimizer component (currently for Windows only)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black-box optimization with Dakota&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currently supported algorithms: Quasi-Newton method, HOPSPACK Asynch Pattern Search, Coliny Evolutionary method (all of them single- and multi-objective) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved "simple wrapper" component&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added Jython as pre- and post-processing scripting language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for OS-independent and multiple commands &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;graphical …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added optimizer component (currently for Windows only)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black-box optimization with Dakota&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currently supported algorithms: Quasi-Newton method, HOPSPACK Asynch Pattern Search, Coliny Evolutionary method (all of them single- and multi-objective) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved "simple wrapper" component&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added Jython as pre- and post-processing scripting language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for OS-independent and multiple commands &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;graphical user interface improvements&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added shortcuts for copy, cut and paste (Crtl+C, Crtl+X, Ctrl+V) in Python editor and text areas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;made several operations asynchronous to improve responsiveness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added zoom to workflow editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added editing of workflow component input values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added information about number of component runs in mouse-over of workflow component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python installation path is now reset properly after moving a workflow to another platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added integrated help for components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added more user-friendly "properties" tab for parametric study component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved Python component usage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added "Profiles" properties tab to enable switching between workflow component properties sets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;removed verbose log output after update &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;raised timeouts to support long running communication between RCE instances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved the build/release/update process&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;made it possible to provide updates for third-party libraries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved versioning to reduce update size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;regrouped installable feature sets (for example, component groups)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved p2 metadata generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for independent RCE editions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.2.5</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-225.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-02-08T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-02-08T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2012-02-08:/release-225.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added Simple Wrapper component (0006339, 0007079)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed Excel component: refresh formula after insertion of data (0007033)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed Excel component: export to Excel(0007034)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed list of platforms involved in a workflow: add the controller platform even no component is running there (0006989, 0006932)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved workflow data browser: add "collapse …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added Simple Wrapper component (0006339, 0007079)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed Excel component: refresh formula after insertion of data (0007033)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed Excel component: export to Excel(0007034)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed list of platforms involved in a workflow: add the controller platform even no component is running there (0006989, 0006932)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved workflow data browser: add "collapse all" icon to (0006762)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved logging in data management catalog backend (0006988)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved logging in communication layer (0006988)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved ComponentInstanceDescriptor with method: getInComponentContextInvolvedPlatforms (0006942)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved workflow editor: add grouping to component list (0007078)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved Pioneer component to serve as a showcase for new GUI features (0006961, 0007029, 0006855)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved SQL command component icon (0007022) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.2.4</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-224.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-01-04T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-01-04T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2012-01-04:/release-224.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed unnecessary undo/redo steps in workflow editor (0006897)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed performance issues when connecting to multiple servers (0006904, 0006900)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed crash issue when running distributed workflows (0006895)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed output channel of Python component firing when it is not assigned in the script (0006921)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed minor workflow-related UI bugs (0006901 …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed unnecessary undo/redo steps in workflow editor (0006897)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed performance issues when connecting to multiple servers (0006904, 0006900)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed crash issue when running distributed workflows (0006895)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed output channel of Python component firing when it is not assigned in the script (0006921)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed minor workflow-related UI bugs (0006901, 0006553)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed issue with transport of workflow information from server to client (0006919)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved logging and debug output (0006898, 0006920, 0006868)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;custom configurations can now be embedded by the product build (0006939)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;workflows with invalid components can now be opened in the editor (0006839)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved "cancel" icon (0006929)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;removed obsolete "edit additional information" feature (0006775)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;internal fixes and enhancements (0006902, 0006810) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.2.3</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-223.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-12-07T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2011-12-07T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2011-12-07:/release-223.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added automatic IP address detection for RCE clients, with fallback option (0006786, 0006843)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for placeholders and properties in JSON configuration files (0006818)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;internal fixes and enhancements (0006849, 0006687) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added automatic IP address detection for RCE clients, with fallback option (0006786, 0006843)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for placeholders and properties in JSON configuration files (0006818)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;internal fixes and enhancements (0006849, 0006687) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Release 2.2.2</title><link href="https://rcenvironment.de/release-222.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-11-15T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2011-11-15T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>RCE</name></author><id>tag:rcenvironment.de,2011-11-15:/release-222.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for xlsx files in Excel (0006760)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added jars related to apache.poi (0006759)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added common code base for tool wrappers (0006640)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added new RCE event log API (0006396)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added test libraries to target platform (0006777)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed: no dirty flag on changes when opening connection manager with context …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support for xlsx files in Excel (0006760)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added jars related to apache.poi (0006759)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added common code base for tool wrappers (0006640)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added new RCE event log API (0006396)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added test libraries to target platform (0006777)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed: no dirty flag on changes when opening connection manager with context menu (0006606)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved performance of workflow data browser (0006626)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved performance for displaying input of remote workflows (0006647)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved Excel component user feedback for doubleclick events in runtime-view (0006658)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;internal changes and fixes (0006774, 0006776, 0006756, 0006662,0006524, 0006676, 0006648) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry></feed>